Jerry D. House

103 Dorchester Drive, Plattsburg, Missouri 64477 Phone: (816) 560-6214 | Email: jdhouse27@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/jdhouse1/ | GitHub: github.com/jdhouse27 |

Portfolio: https://jdhouse27.github.io/Portfolio/

Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in healthcare, customer service, and retail. Leader by example with over 9 years experience in technology, project management, and leadership. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Acknowledged by peers for attention to detail and determination to complete every project.

Technical Skills

Node.Js | Express | JavaScript | jQuery | React.js | React | GIT | GitHub | MongoDB | MySQL | Firebase | HTML | CSS | Bootstrap | Various CSS Frameworks | Media Queries | APIs | JSON | AJAX | Handlebars | Excel | Microsoft Suite | Heroku |

Projects

Scenic | https://jdhouse27.github.io/Project2/. | https://oneprotwo.herokuapp.com/

- Project task was to design a full stack application where a user could select a desired city and then be able to find something that interests them. The user could then select to add to an itinerary for use
- Core responsibilities were project lead, back-end design and build, as well as build and design for the landing search page.
- HTML5, CSS, UIKit, MySQL, Javascript, JQuery, Firebase, API, Express, Heroku, GIT

Fuel Me Now | https://jdhouse27.github.io/Fuel-Me-Now/.

- Project task was to design an application for users to be able to locate local gas stations and purchase gas for delivery
- Core responsibilities were initial front in design and build
- HTML5, CSS, Javascript, JQuery, Firebase, API, GIT

Experience

Support Analyst - Retail Systems Management

April 2019-Present

- Provide next day support for end users post Microsoft Windows upgrade.
- Troubleshoot issues, such as connectivity, hardware, or software issues ensuring successful and complete upgrade.

General Manager/Owner Operator - Big Whiskey's

May 2017-March 2019

- Ran day to day operations.
- Maintained employee schedules to effectively decrease labor by 8%.
- Increased sales by 15% through guest and employee satisfaction.
- Maintained a quality product while controlling inventory costs.
- Responsible for training staff and maintaining proper staffing.

Application Support Analyst - Mosaic Life Care

April 2014-December 2018

- Built lab and pharmacy orders per end user request.
- Built and displayed lab order results per end user request.
- Built rules to facilitate better functionality for end users.
- Modified build for accurate charges.
- Wrote SQL type queries for data retrieval.

Respiratory Therapy - Mosaic Life Care

September 2009-April 2014

- Administered various Respiratory Therapies to patients.
- Promoted to shift leader within first year.
- Educated patients, family members, and peers of respiratory care.
- Contributed in team meetings and collaborated with management in the decisionmaking process.

Education

Coding Bootcamp Certificate: Kansas University, Overland Park, KS A 24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Respiratory Therapy: Concorde Career College, Kansas City, MO (Associates Degree and Certificate)

A 18 month followed by another 9 month program focused on gaining valuable lifesaving clinical knowledge of respiratory care.